<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-01-03T15:15:23+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">FDI</title><subtitle>Academic webpage of Dr. Guancai Xie</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Open-circuit potential and photovoltage in photoelectrodes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/06/ocp_pv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open-circuit potential and photovoltage in photoelectrodes" /><published>2022-12-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/06/ocp_pv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/06/ocp_pv.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The open-circuit potential</strong> (OCP, $V_\mathrm{oc}$) is the potential of the work electrode (WE) relative to the reference electrode (RE) under open-circuit condition (no potential or current is being applied to the cell). It can be established by leaving the potential of the WE uncontrolled, allowing it to achieve equilibrium with the electrolyte. This can be done in both the light and the dark. The open circuit potential is obtained by monitoring the rate of change of the WE potential until it is negligible.</p>

<p>For a PEC water splitting device, the redox couples of interest are the H$^+$/$\mathrm{H_2}$ couple for a p-type semiconductor photocathode, and the $\mathrm{O_2}$/$\mathrm{H_2}$O couple for an n-type semiconductor photoanode. In the case of an n-type semiconductor, the established thermodynamic equilibrium ($E_F = E_\mathrm{O_2/H_2O}$) between the semiconductor and the electrolyte results in an upward band bending of the semiconductor surface. In the dark, the measured $V_\mathrm{oc-dark}$ is thus the $E_F / E_\mathrm{O_2/H_2O}$ relative to the RE. Whereas in the light, the $E_\mathrm{F_n}$ rises because of the higher occupancy of the conduction band and the $E_\mathrm{F_p}$ equilibrates with the $E_\mathrm{redox}$ ($E_\mathrm{F_p} = E_\mathrm{O_2/H_2O}$). The measured $V_\mathrm{oc-light}$ is thus the $E_\mathrm{F_n}$ relative to the RE. Furthermore, under illumination, the photogenerated holes can accumulate at the surface lowering the barrier for electrons with increasing light intensity until the electrons can reach the surface at the same rate as holes, at which condition the measured $V_\mathrm{oc-light}$ approximates the $V_\mathrm{fb}$ versus the RE.</p>

<p><strong>The photovoltage $V_\mathrm{ph}$</strong> generated by the semiconductor is given by the difference between the hole and electron quasi-Fermi levels under illumination, that is, by the free energy difference between the majority carriers and the photoexcited minority carriers. Illuminating the electrode surface will shift the Fermi level of the bulk (measured $V_\mathrm{oc}$) towards more anodic potentials for a p-type material and towards more cathodic potentials for a n-type material. Accordingly,</p>

\[V_\mathrm{ph} = |E_\mathrm{f_n}-E_\mathrm{f_p}|=|V_\mathrm{oc-light}-V_\mathrm{oc-dark}|\]

<p>Note, however, that the $V_\mathrm{ph}$ measured at open circuit may not exactly reﬂect the $V_\mathrm{ph}$ under operating conditions since the latter must also include the kinetic overpotential for the reaction of interest.</p>

<p>The ideal OCP should be equal to a value of $V_\mathrm{bi}$ tha tis determined by the Fermi level difference of the two materials. Neverthless, the actual OCP values display a $V_\mathrm{ph}$ that is determined by quasi-Fermi level splitting and is affected by photovoltaic losses arising because of charge generation, separation, and recombination. In this regard, a dynamic change in</p>

<p><strong>Reference:</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting Standards, Experimental Methods, and Protocols. 2013, Springer.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Walter M G, Warren E L, McKone J R, et al. Solar water splitting cells. Chemical Reviews, 2010, 110(11): 6446-6473</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="PC-PEC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The open-circuit potential (OCP, $V_\mathrm{oc}$) is the potential of the work electrode (WE) relative to the reference electrode (RE) under open-circuit condition (no potential or current is being applied to the cell). It can be established by leaving the potential of the WE uncontrolled, allowing it to achieve equilibrium with the electrolyte. This can be done in both the light and the dark. The open circuit potential is obtained by monitoring the rate of change of the WE potential until it is negligible.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work function of metal oxides</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/05/workfunc_mo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work function of metal oxides" /><published>2022-12-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/05/workfunc_mo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/05/workfunc_mo.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/wiki/.pdf" width="100%" /></p>

<p>Reference:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Universal energy-level alignment of molecules on metal oxides</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Data" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Metrics for evaluating PEC performance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/pec_metric.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metrics for evaluating PEC performance" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/pec_metric</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/pec_metric.html"><![CDATA[<p>By definition, the efficiency for any process that converts energy from one form to another is the ratio of the total power output to the total power input. For PEC systems, the <strong>solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiency</strong> is the single value by which all PEC devices can be reliably ranked against one another, which can be directly determined by analysis of the hydrogen formed under solar AM 1.5G illumination <u>in the absence of an applied bias</u>. For a correct STH efficiency measurement, the working electrode (WE) and counter electrode (CE) should be short-circuited, which infers that STH is <u>measured in a 2-electrode system</u>. Besides, one must have both the WE and CE immersed in the same pH solution. In addition, <u>the electrolyte should not contain any sacrificial donors or acceptors</u>.</p>

<p><strong>STH</strong> can be calculated from the product of the rate of hydrogen production $r_\mathrm{H_2}$ (mmol/s) and the gain in Gibbs energy $\Delta G$ (237 kJ mol$^{−1}$).</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{STH}}=\left[\frac{r_{\mathrm{H}_2} \times \Delta G}{P_{\text {total }} \times S}\right]_{\mathrm{AM} 1.5 \mathrm{G}}\]

<p>where $P_\textrm{total}$ is the energy flux of the sunlight (mW/cm$^2$) and <em>S</em> is the illuminated photoelectrode area (cm$^2$). Or, it can be calculated from the product of voltage, current, and the <strong>faradaic efficiency</strong> for hydrogen evolution $\eta_F$.</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{STH}}=\left[\frac{\left|J_{\mathrm{SC}}\right| \times 1.23(\mathrm{~V}) \times \eta_{\mathrm{F}}}{P_{\text {total }}}\right]_{\mathrm{AM} 1.5 \mathrm{G}}\]

<p>where$ J_\mathrm{SC}$ is the short-circuit photocurrent density (mA/cm$^2$) normalized to the illuminated electrode area.</p>

<p>For PEC systems that require an external bias to split water, $\eta_\textrm{STH}$ is zero. However, other metrics are invaluable scientifically and can be employed to provide insight into the functionality and limitations of a PEC device. <u>These metrics including applied-bias photon-to-current efficiency (ABPE), half-cell solar-to-hydrogen efficiency (HC-STH), external quantum efficiency (EQE) = incident photon-to-current efficiency (IPCE), and internal quantum efficiency (IQE) = absorbed photon-to-current efficiency (APCE) are called diagnostic efficiencies.</u></p>

<p><strong>ABPE</strong> measures the net chemical output power (rate of production of free energy of products less the input electrical power) of a system in units of incident solar power, and it represents the fraction of the energy stored in the chemical products that can be assigned to the photovoltage provided by the input solar illumination. It is frequently used for two-electrode measurements when an external voltage is applied to PEC systems as the electrical energy has to be subtracted from the energy gain. As with STH, ABPE measurements also require that both the WE and CE should be immersed in the same pH solution and the electrolyte should not contain any sacrificial donors or acceptors. ABPE is the difference of the power output in chemical fuel and any added electrical input power, divided by the solar power input.</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{ABPE}}=\left[\frac{\left|J_{\mathrm{ph}}\right| \times\left(1.23-V_{\mathrm{b}}\right) \times \eta_{\mathrm{F}}}{P_{\text {total }}}\right]_{\mathrm{AM} 1.5 \mathrm{G}}\]

<p>where $J_\textrm{ph}$ (mA/cm$^2$) is the photocurrent density obtained under an applied bias V$_\textrm{b}$ (V).</p>

<p>For a photoanode (photocathode) measured in the three-electrode configuration, the product of the potential gain and the photocurrent could be regarded as the hypothetical <strong>HC-STH</strong>. The gain in potential by PEC water splitting could be approximated by the difference of the potential of a photoanode (photocathode) from the oxygen (hydrogen) equilibrium potential:</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{HC}-\mathrm{STH}}=\left\{\begin{array}{l}
{\left[\frac{\left|J_{\mathrm{ph}}\right| \times\left(E_{\mathrm{O}_2 / \mathrm{H}_2 \mathrm{O}}-E_{\mathrm{b}}\right)}{P_{\text {total }}}\right]_{\mathrm{AM} 1.5 \mathrm{G}}} \\
{\left[\frac{\left[J_{\mathrm{ph}} \mid \times\left(E_{\mathrm{b}}-E_{\mathrm{H}^{+} / \mathrm{H} 2}\right)\right.}{P_{\text {total }}}\right]_{\mathrm{AM} 1.5 \mathrm{G}}}
\end{array}\right.\]

<p>where $E_\textrm{b}$ is the applied potential (<em>vs.</em> RHE). $E_\mathrm{O_2/H_2O}$ and $E_\mathrm{H^+/H_2}$ stand for the equilibrium potentials of oxygen evolution (+1.23 V <em>vs.</em> RHE) and hydrogen evolution (0 V <em>vs.</em> RHE), respectively. Provided that $η_F$ of PEC water splitting is unity and that a counter electrode drives the counter reaction without any overpotential, HC-STH is a convenient estimate of maximum ABPE of a half-cell independent of properties of a counter electrode. In reality, however, the potential of a counter electrode is not equilibrated with the potential of the redox reaction on the counter electrode as mentioned in the previous section. Therefore, HC-STH should not be regarded as ABPE.</p>

<p><strong>IPCE</strong> describes the photocurrent collected per incident photon flux as a function of illumination wavelength. The researcher can ideally integrate the IPCE data over the solar spectrum to estimate the maximum possible STH efficiency for that device, but only for the IPCE data collected under zero bias (2-electrode, short-circuit) conditions. IPCE under an applied bias is not considered a valid estimate for STH, but it is still a useful diagnostic tool that gives insight into the PEC material properties because it yields device efficiency in terms of “electrons out per photons in”. IPCE takes into account efficiencies for three fundamental processes involved in PEC: photon absorptance, defined as the fraction of electron-hole pairs generated per incident photon flux ($\eta_{e­^-/h^+}$), charge transport to the solid-liquid interface ($\eta_\textrm{charge separation}$), and the efficiency of interfacial charge transfer ($\eta_\textrm{charge injection}$). This method assumes that the counter electrode is not limiting current flowing through the circuit.</p>

\[\text { IPCE }=\eta_{\mathrm{e}^{-}/\mathrm{h^+}} \times \eta_{\text {charge separation }} \times \eta_{\text {charge injection }}\]

<p>where</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{e}^{-} / \mathrm{h}^{+}}=\frac{I_0-I}{I}=1-10^{-A_e}\]

<p>where $A$ is the absorbance of a sample defined as the logarithmic ratio of the measured output light intensity ($I$) versus the initial input light intensity ($I_0$).</p>

<p>IPCE is usually obtained from a chronoamperometry (potentiostatic) measurement. In this system, a bias can be applied between the sample/working electrode versus a counter electrode (2-electrode experiment) or a reference electrode (3-electrode experiment) while measuring the current that arises from subjecting the PEC electrode to monochromatic light at various wavelengths. The difference between the steady-state current under monochromatic illumination and the steady-state background current is the photocurrent that arises due to redox reactions occurring at the surface of the working and counter electrodes.</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{IPCE}}=\frac{\text { electrons }}{\text { photons }}=\frac{\left|J_{\mathrm{ph}}\right| \times h c}{P_{\text {mono }} \times \lambda}\]

<p>where $P_\textrm{mono}$ is the calibrated and monochromated illumination power intensity (mW/cm$^2$), and $\lambda$ (nm) is the wavelength at which this illumination power is measured. Besides, the integration of IPCE over the entire solar spectrum can provide an estimation of the maximum possible STH, if (and only if) no applied bias is used in the IPCE measurement.</p>

<p><strong>APCE</strong> describes the photocurrent collected per incident photon absorbed. This value is a particularly useful quantity to measure when studying thin films, because it helps to determine the optimum balance between maximal path length for photon absorption versus minimal effective carrier transport distance within the material.</p>

\[\text { APCE }=\frac{\text { IPCE }}{\eta_{\mathrm{e}^{-} / \mathrm{h}^{+}}}=\eta_{\text {charge separation }} \times \eta_{\text {charge injection }}\]

<p>By combining the equations for determining IPCE and $\eta_{e­^-/h^+}$ experimentally, we can derive APCE as follows:</p>

\[\eta_{\mathrm{APCE}}=\frac{\left|J_{\mathrm{ph}}\right| \times h c}{P_{\text {mono }} \times \lambda \times\left(1-10^{-A}\right)}\]

<p>Reference:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Chen Z, et al. Accelerating materials development for photoelectrochemical hydrogen production: Standards for methods, definitions, and reporting protocols. J. Mater. Res., 2010, 25(01): 3-16.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hisatomi T, et al. Recent advances in semiconductors for photocatalytic and photoelectrochemical water splitting. Chem. Soc. Rev., 2014, 43(22): 7520-7535.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="PC-PEC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[By definition, the efficiency for any process that converts energy from one form to another is the ratio of the total power output to the total power input. For PEC systems, the solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiency is the single value by which all PEC devices can be reliably ranked against one another, which can be directly determined by analysis of the hydrogen formed under solar AM 1.5G illumination in the absence of an applied bias. For a correct STH efficiency measurement, the working electrode (WE) and counter electrode (CE) should be short-circuited, which infers that STH is measured in a 2-electrode system. Besides, one must have both the WE and CE immersed in the same pH solution. In addition, the electrolyte should not contain any sacrificial donors or acceptors.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Work function of metals</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/workfunc_metal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work function of metals" /><published>2022-12-04T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/workfunc_metal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/04/workfunc_metal.html"><![CDATA[<p>The electron work function Φ is a measure of the minimum energy required to extract an electron from the surface of a solid. It is defined more precisely as the energy difference between the state in which an electron has been removed to a distance from the surface of a single crystal face that is large enough that the image force is negligible but small compared to the distance to any other face (typically about 10$^{-4}$ cm) and the state in which the electron is in the bulk solid. In general, Φ differs for each face of a monocrystalline sample.</p>

<p>Because Φ is dependent on the cleanliness of the surface, measurements reported in the literature often cover a considerable range (Refs. 1-4). This table contains selected values for the electron work function of the elements which may be regarded as typical values for a reasonably clean surface. The table contains recommended values from a recent review that includes estimated uncertainties (see Ref. 1 for more details). Those values, marked R in the table, come from analysis of results from different measurement methods. The method of measurement is indicated for each value. The following abbreviations appear:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Abbre.</th>
      <th>Full name</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">R –</td>
      <td>Recommended value from Ref. 1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">TE –</td>
      <td>Thermionic emission</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">PE –</td>
      <td>Photoelectric effect</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">FE –</td>
      <td>Field emission</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">CPD –</td>
      <td>Contact potential difference</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">polycr –</td>
      <td>Polycrystalline sample</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">amorp –</td>
      <td>Amorphous sample</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><img src="/images/wiki/metalwf.pdf" width="100%" /></p>

<p>Reference:</p>

<ol>
  <li>https://hbcp.chemnetbase.com/faces/documents/12_21/12_21_0001.xhtml</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Data" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The electron work function Φ is a measure of the minimum energy required to extract an electron from the surface of a solid. It is defined more precisely as the energy difference between the state in which an electron has been removed to a distance from the surface of a single crystal face that is large enough that the image force is negligible but small compared to the distance to any other face (typically about 10$^{-4}$ cm) and the state in which the electron is in the bulk solid. In general, Φ differs for each face of a monocrystalline sample.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mott-Schottky analysis in photo(electro)catalytic experiments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/03/mott_schottky.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mott-Schottky analysis in photo(electro)catalytic experiments" /><published>2022-12-03T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/03/mott_schottky</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/03/mott_schottky.html"><![CDATA[<p> Assuming only the space-charge capacitance that varies with the changing electrode
potential, the reverse-bias dependence of the inverse square capacitance of the space-charge region in the semiconductor is given by the Mott-Schottky relation: <!--more--></p>

\[\frac{1}{C^2}=\frac{2}{A^2\epsilon\epsilon_0 q N_D}(E-E_\textrm{fb}-\frac{kT}{q})\]

<p>where $C$ is the relative permittivity of Si (11.7), $q$ is the elementary charge, $N_D$ is the free charge carrier density in the semiconductor, $E$ is the potential difference between the semiconductor and the redox potential of the solution, $E_\textrm{fb}$ is the flat band potential, $k$ is the Boltzmann’s constant and $T$ is temperature (298 K).</p>

<p> Mott-Schottky is an electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) technique that can be difﬁcult to perform and interpret if the system is not ideal. When the measurement is successful, it is able to determine both the $E_\textrm{fb}$ and the free charge carrier density (donors or acceptors, $N_D$) of the photoelectrode. The Mott-Schottky plot will possess a negative slope for p-type materials and a positive slope for n-type materials.</p>

<p>The primary disadvantage of M–S analysis is that the C sc of a photoelectrode can
be very complicated to measure depending on the sample composition and mor-
phology. The ideal sample is a single-crystal material of high crystalline quality
with moderate doping grown on an ohmic contact. Single-frequency measurements
of the C sc of an ideal sample are fairly straightforward. However, measurements
for samples which are not ideal may require a full evaluation of the frequency
range over many decades, followed by ﬁtting of the data to an appropriate, but
often complicated equivalent circuit model</p>

<p>The $E_\textrm{fb}$ can be determined by taking the value of the intercept between the extrapolated linear region of the $C^{−2}$ with the $x$-axis in the Mott-Schottky plot.</p>

<p> The barrier height ($\phi_b$) was calculated using the Schottky’s relation:
 \(\phi_b=E_\textrm{fb}+V_n\)</p>

<p>Where $V_n$ is the difference between the potential of the conduction band edge and the Fermi level, and was obtained by using the following relationship:</p>

\[V_n=kT\,\textrm{ln}(\frac{N_C}{N_D})\]

<p>The density of conduction band states ($N_C$) was calculated by</p>

\[N_C=2(\frac{2\pi m^*_ekT}{h^2})^{3/2}\]

<p>where $m^*_e$ is the effective mass of electron and  $h$ is the Planck’s constant.</p>

<p><strong>Example</strong></p>

<p><strong>Reference</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="PC-PEC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ Assuming only the space-charge capacitance that varies with the changing electrode potential, the reverse-bias dependence of the inverse square capacitance of the space-charge region in the semiconductor is given by the Mott-Schottky relation:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Calculation of the theoretical maximum photocurrent</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/02/thoery_j.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Calculation of the theoretical maximum photocurrent" /><published>2022-12-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/02/thoery_j</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/02/thoery_j.html"><![CDATA[<p> Let us assume that we have an ideal photoelectrode with no optical losses. The attainable current density for a given bandgap is then obtained by integrating the spectral distribution. Starting value is the band gap energy and the integration runs over all shorter wavelengths. If we plot the value of the integral for different starting points we get the maximum current density for a given bandgap. This is the maximum current that the photoelectrode can deliver under short circuit conditions. Lower bandgaps yield higher currents because they absorb larger parts of the spectrum. <!--more--></p>

<p> The theoretical maximum photocurrent density under light illumination, $J_\textrm{max} (A\,m^{-2})$, is calculated by integrating the photon flux, shown in equation:</p>

\[J_\textrm{max}=e\times \int \limits_{\lambda_a}^{\lambda_b}\textrm{Flux}(\lambda)d\lambda\]

<p>where $\lambda_a$ is the shortest wavelength of the light emitted by the light source ($m$), $\lambda_b$ is the wavelength of the absorption edge of photoelectrode ($m$), $e$ is the charge of single electron ($1.602\times 10^{-19}\, C$), and $\lambda$ is the wavelength of the incident monochromatic light ($m$). Flux($\lambda$) is the photon flux of the light source ($m^{-2}\, s^{-1}\, nm^{-1}$), and it is calculated according to:</p>

\[\textrm{Flux}(\lambda)=P(\lambda)E(\lambda)\]

<p>where $P(\lambda)$ is the power of incident photons ($W\, m^{-2}\, nm^{-1}$). $E(\lambda)$ is the photon energy ($J$) and it is calculated from</p>

\[E(\lambda)=hc/\lambda\]

<p>where $h$ is Planck’s constant ($6.626\times 10^{-34}\, J\, s$), $c$ is the speed of light ($3\times 10^8\, m\, s^{-1}$).</p>

<p> Thus,</p>

\[J_\textrm{max}=e\times \int \limits_{\lambda_a}^{\lambda_b}\frac{P(\lambda)\lambda}{hc}d\lambda\]

<p><strong>Example</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/wiki/AM15-1.png" alt="Image" /></p>

<p><strong>Figure</strong> <strong>1</strong> (left) AM1.5 spectrum. (right) Converted current per area and time and wavelength interval (black) and maximum attainable photocurrent for a given bandgap (red), assuming an AM1.5 spectrum.</p>

<p>Reference:</p>

<p>http://www.superstrate.net/pv/limit/</p>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="PC-PEC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ Let us assume that we have an ideal photoelectrode with no optical losses. The attainable current density for a given bandgap is then obtained by integrating the spectral distribution. Starting value is the band gap energy and the integration runs over all shorter wavelengths. If we plot the value of the integral for different starting points we get the maximum current density for a given bandgap. This is the maximum current that the photoelectrode can deliver under short circuit conditions. Lower bandgaps yield higher currents because they absorb larger parts of the spectrum.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Measurement of the charge separation and injection yields</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/sep&inj_eff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Measurement of the charge separation and injection yields" /><published>2022-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-12-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/sep&amp;inj_eff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/01/sep&amp;inj_eff.html"><![CDATA[<p> The water splitting photocurrent ($J^\mathrm{H_2O} _\textrm{photocurrent}$) is a product of the rate of photon absorption expressed as a current density ($J _\textrm{absorbed}$), the charge separation yield of the photogenerated carriers ($\eta _\textrm{charge separation}$), and charge injection yield to the electrolyte ($\eta _\textrm{charge injection}$): 
<!--more--></p>

\[J ^\mathrm{H_2O} _\textrm{photocurrent} = J _\textrm{absorbed} \times \eta _\textrm{charge separation} \times \eta _\textrm{charge injection}\]

<p>Where $\eta_\textrm{charge separation}$ is the yield of the photogenerated electrons/holes that reach the electrode/electrolyte interface or, in other words, the fraction of photogenerated electrons/holes that does not recombine with holes/electrons in the bulk of photoelectrodes. $\eta _\textrm{charge injection}$ is the yield of those electrons/holes that have reached the electrode/electrolyte interface and that are injected into the electrolyte to reduce/oxidize the water, or in other words, do not recombine with holes/electrons at surface traps. $J _\textrm{absorbed}$ is the current density converted from the absorbed photons when assuming that the absorbed photons are completely converted into electrons (APCE=100%), and it can be calculated by using the equation:</p>

\[J_\textrm{absorbed} = e\times\int\limits_{\lambda_a}^{\lambda_b}\frac{P(\lambda)}{\frac{hc}{\lambda}}A(\lambda)d\lambda = \frac{e}{hc}\times \int\limits_{\lambda_a}^{\lambda_b} P(\lambda)A(\lambda) \lambda d\lambda\]

<p>where $ \lambda_a$ is the shortest wavelength of the light emitted by the light source, $ \lambda_b$ is the wavelength of the absorption edge of the photoelectrode. $P$,$\lambda$, $h$, $c$, $e$, and $A$ are the power of incident photons, the wavelength of the incident monochromatic light, the Planck constant, the light speed, the charge of single electron, and the absorbance of the photoelectrode, respectively.</p>

<p> On the other hand, $\eta_\textrm{charge separation}$ is assumed to become 100% ($\eta_\textrm{charge injection} = 1$) in the presence of electron scavenger (usually ascorbic acid) or hole scavenger (usually H$_2$O$_2$ or Na$_2$SO$ _3$) in the electrolyte, then the photocurrent measured with scavenger in the electrolyte ($J^\textrm{scavenger} _\textrm{photocurrent}$) is a product of $J _\textrm{absorbed}$ and $\eta _\textrm{charge separation}$ only:</p>

\[J^\textrm{scavenger} _\textrm{photocurrent}=J _\textrm{absorbed}\times\eta _\textrm{charge separation}\]

<p>So, the $\eta_\textrm{charge separation}$ and $\eta_\textrm{charge injection}$ can be calculated by</p>

\[\eta _\textrm{charge separation}= J^\textrm{scavenger} _\textrm{photocurrent} /J _\textrm{absorbed}\]

\[\eta _\textrm{charge injection}=J^\mathrm{H_2O} _\textrm{photocurrent}/J^\textrm{scavenger} _\textrm{photocurrent}\]

<p><strong>Notes:</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>The scavenger used should be transparent to visible and UV light, does not corrode the photoelectrode, and importantly the injection barrier is removed and the surface recombination is suppressed. (No transient photocurrent in the chopped light J-t measurement)</li>
  <li>The band bending should remain the same in both electrolyte solution (with and without the scavenger), namely, the flat band potential should be the same from Mott-Schottky measurement.</li>
  <li>The C program used to process the charge separation and injection yields can be downloaded from <a href="">to be added</a>.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Example:</strong></p>

<p><strong>Reference:</strong></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Dotan, H. et al. Probing the Photoelectrochemical Properties of Hematite (α-Fe$_2$O$_3$) Electrodes Using Hydrogen Peroxide as a Hole Scavenger. <em>Energy Environ. Sci.</em> <strong>2011</strong>, <em>4</em> (3), 958.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Li, J, et al. Superior Visible Light Hydrogen Evolution of Janus Bilayer Junctions via Atomic-Level Charge Flow Steering. <em>Nat. Commun.</em> <strong>2016</strong>, <em>7</em>, 11480.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Guancai Xie</name><email>man.xiegc@gmail.com</email></author><category term="PC-PEC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ The water splitting photocurrent ($J^\mathrm{H_2O} _\textrm{photocurrent}$) is a product of the rate of photon absorption expressed as a current density ($J _\textrm{absorbed}$), the charge separation yield of the photogenerated carriers ($\eta _\textrm{charge separation}$), and charge injection yield to the electrolyte ($\eta _\textrm{charge injection}$):]]></summary></entry></feed>